Name: Valentina Nikolaeva

Address: Bulgaria, Sofia, Mladost 4

Phone: +359899149987

Email: valnklv@gmail.com

Summary: Abilities gained in areas of Software Development and Testing, Software Support Assistance in a Clinical Research Organization, Document creation and coordination for Trading and Manufacturing companies.

Continuous strive for excellence in the quality of well done day to day tasks delivery. Enjoying communication, learning, exchanging experience with people from diverse backgrounds united with Team's spirit to work together and have as precedence the effective results and excellence in collaborations.

Keywords / Skill Set: Microsoft Office, Technical Support, Quality Assurance, Functional Testing, UI Testing, Accessibility Testing, Teamwork, Customer Service, Analytical Skills, Scrum, Business Process Improvement, Troubleshooting.

Languages: Bulgarian, English, Russian.

Employment History:

July 2017 - April 2020

Senior Quality Assurance

Resources used: Bugzilla, TFS, Visual Studio, Microsoft Products - workflow oriented, SharePoint, Mongo DB, Jira, Postman, TestLink, TestRail, Confluence, Skype for Business, Webex, Slack.

Main responsibilities:

1

Provide support for multiple products and systems, while participating on different projects

Participate none technical meetings on demand.

Evaluate application requirements and design documents, working closely with Product Management, systems engineers.

Create and maintains test data, progression and regression test suites, but not limited to: Functional, and none Functional testing.

Report, research, validate and track defects. Monitoring and improving the quality documentations.

May 2013 - July 2017 - Axway

Quality Engineer

Resources used: HP alm, Jira, Mantis Peoplesoft, Outlook, Wiki

Main responsibilities:

Manage defects lifecycle (reporting, tracking, escalation, verification). Using bug-tracking systems: HP alm, Jyra, Mantis, Bugzilla.

Analysis, design and execution of manual tests such as End to End, Integration, Acceptance, Functional, Regression, Smoke and Sanity tests.

Monitoring and improving the quality documentations.

May 2012 - July 2013 - C3i Europe

Team Lead

Resources used: Oracle – OC RDC, Horizon, Outlook

Main responsibilities:

Monitor Daily Help Desk activities:

- Monitoring attendance and break schedule;
- Monitor real time call stats and agents availability.

QA - Perform QAs of technicians interactions with field customers and provide remediation as necessary.

Reporting and analysis - Reporting on daily, weekly and monthly basis.

Act as first level of management escalation for issues requiring leadership attention.

Working with potentially upset customers.

Internal and external clients communication.

Participation in ongoing projects and improvements implementation.

Interact with the L1/L2/L3 technicians on daily basis in order to ensure that high quality service is provided to the client.

Daily tasks distribution and completion supervision.

Ensure that all Service Level Agreements (deadlines and quality) are met.

Collaborate with other line functions to find workarounds and long term solutions.

Oct 2010- July 2012 - C3i Europe

Support Help Desk Analyst Level II

Resources used: Oracle, Windows, Outlook, SharePoint, OCRDC, Oracle, CISCO VPN, Siebel client specific applications

Main responsibilities:

Distributing and monitoring tasks to Level I Technicians, monitoring completion as per company's SOPs.

Performing monthly QC and QA of the work of the Level I Technicians monitoring and remediating their work.

Communicating with end clients, handling technical issues, processing them.

General knowledge of Windows, Outlook, SharePoint, OCRDC, Oracle

Clinical, troubleshooting other multiple clinical applications, following company's internal determined SLAs.

Running reports from an internal tracking system for Tier 2 teams and for other reporting analysis, reporting to the upper level of management.

Jun 2008-Oct 2010 - C3i Europe

Support Help Desk Analyst Level I

Resources used: Oracle, Windows, Outlook, SharePoint, OCRDC, Oracle, CISCO VPN, Siebel client specific applications

Main responsibilities:

Provide professional and timely technical support to the service desk customers

Identify, troubleshoot and resolve customer problems by utilizing all technical resources available while adhering to strict quality standards and regulatory requirements

Effectively prioritize and manage technical problems

Resolving incoming telephone/email requests for technical assistance on standard commercial and proprietary applications (such as MS Office applications, Windows OS, CISCO VPN, Siebel, client specific applications)

Logging and assigning any appeared issues in the company's tracking system

Escalating issues that cannot be resolved locally

Education:

• 1995 – 2000, Technical University Sofia, Bulgaria,

Engineer – manager, Industrial management, Magister

• 1995 - "Ivan Vazov", Plovdiv, language school

Interpreting skills: Russian; English

Certifications:

- Microsoft Office Excel 2007 New Horizons Computer Learning Centers Sofia, Bulgaria;
- Proactive Initiative, Creativity and Problem Solving Arthur Adams Business Training Centre;
- CCNA- I st level Cicso Sofia, Bulgaria;
- Introduction to Presenting Information- MS PowerPoint Valleymedia London, UK;
- Word Processing MS Word 95+, Microsoft Excel 2007 Valleymedia London, UK;

Courses:

- Quick-Start Javascript 2020 Udemy
- ISTQB Foundation Level Quality House Sofia, Bulgaria